

Biography.

I am currently a senior researcher in Damo Academic at Alibaba Group. I obtained my M.S and B.S degrees from Peking University and Beijing Jiaotong University, respectively. My research interests are in the areas of neural radiance field, generative model, and deepfake detection. I have published several highly-regarded papers in these topics and have garnered **500+** citations. Find more details about my research on **google scholar** or my **homepage**

Education

Peking University

Beijing, China

M.S. IN SOFTWARE ENGINEERING

Aug. 2017 - July. 2020

• 1st place in the graduate student entrance examination(1/175)

• GPA 3.77/4.0

Beijing Jiaotong University

Beijing, China

Aug. 2013 - Jun. 2017

B.S. IN COMMUNICATION ENGINEERING

• GPA 84.2/100

Experience

Alibaba DAMO Academy

Beijing, China

SENIOR RESEARCHER

July. 2020 - PRESENT

 Member of the XR lab, Researching and developing State-of-the-Art algorithms about dynamic NeRF, volumetric NeRF compression, super high resolution NeRF, facial motion retargeting, face replacement and face cartoonization. related project have been launched in Alibaba Cloud.

Microsoft Research Asia Beijing, China

RESEARCH INTERN Aug. 2018 - June. 2020

• Member of the Computer Vision group, supervised by Dong Chen. Research in deepfake detection, face replacement and semantic segmentation. related project have been launched in Azure.

Publication

Compressing Volumetric Radiance Fields to 1 MB

LINGZHI LI*, ZHEN SHEN*, ZHONGSHU WANG, LI SHEN, LIEFENG BO arXiv:2211.16386

4K-NeRF: High Fidelity Neural Radiance Fields at Ultra High Resolutions

ZHONGSHU WANG, **LINGZHI LI**, ZHEN SHEN, LI SHEN, LIEFENG BO

Your3dEmoji: Creating Personalized Emojis via One-shot 3D-aware Cartoon Avatar Synthesis

Shiyao Xu, **Lingzhi Li**, Li Shen, Yifang Men, Zhouhui Lian Siggraph Asia 2022 Technical Communication

Streaming Radiance Fields for 3D Video Synthesis

Lingzhi Li, Zhen Shen, Zhongshu Wang, Li Shen, Ping Tan NeurIPS 2022

Face X-ray for More General Face Forgery Detection

Lingzhi Li*, Jianming Bao*, Ting Zhang, Yang Hao, Dong Chen, Fang Wen, Baining Guo CVPR 2020 **Oral**

FaceShifter: Towards High Fidelity And Occlusion Aware Face Swapping

LINGZHI LI, JIANMING BAO, YANG HAO, DONG CHEN, FANG WEN CVPR 2020 **Oral**

Honors & Awards _____

2020	Stars of Tomorrow, Microsoft Research Asia (Award of Excellent Intern)	Beijing, China
2018	1st , Jane Street Electronic Trading Competition	Beijing, China
2018	2nd , Citadel Data-Open Beijing	Beijing, China
2018	Merit Student, Academic awards of Peking University	Beijing, China
2018	39th/3634 , Data Science Bowl, Automate Nucleus Detection Chanllenge	U.S.A
2017	5th/274 , WWW 2018 Musical Genre Classification Challenge	Lyon, Fance

Academic Service _____

Conference Reviewer

- Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition Conference.
- European Conference on Computer Vision.
- IEEE Transactions on Image Processing.
- IEEE Transactions on Multimedia.
- AAAI conference on artificial intelligence.